<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webrtc on MG Blog</title>
    <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/tags/webrtc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webrtc on MG Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 15:42:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mridulganga.github.io/tags/webrtc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC, what&#39;s that?</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 15:42:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-basics/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Iresh Sharma &amp;amp; Mridul Ganga
What is WebRTC? WebRTC stands for web real-time communication, it is an open standard for real-time communications over the internet. With Webrtc you can implement realtime video, voice and data transfer between various peers, this technology is available for almost any browser and provides native clients for most platforms including android and iOS.
What can we do with WebRTC? The application of WebRTC can range from anywhere between a simple chatting application, to full-fledged audio and video conferencing applications, file transfer applications etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC using Peerjs</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:26:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean when we say peer to peer? P2P is direct connection between two devices to transfer data to-and-fro without the need of a central server. The traffic does not go to or from any central server, but directly from one device to the other.
What is WebRTC? WebRTC stands for web real-time communications. WebRTC was not supported by all the browsers until recently and is also available in most mobile browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>