<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MG Blog</title>
    <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MG Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 20:43:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mridulganga.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Most popular Temporal Paradoxes</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/temporal-paradoxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 20:43:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/temporal-paradoxes/</guid>
      <description>A temporal paradox, time paradox, or time travel paradox is an apparent contradiction, or logical contradiction associated with the idea of time and time travel.
Causal Loop The causal loop is a paradox in which a future event causes the past event which leads to the future event. For example a billiard ball moves to a time travel machine and travels to its past and strikes the past self towards the time machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple systemd on Linux</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/systemd-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 20:15:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/systemd-basic/</guid>
      <description>Below is a super simple guide to creating a systemd service on linux. Systemd is not yet supported on all the linux systems, but it&amp;rsquo;s popular and easy to use.
What is systemd? systemd is a Linux initialization system and service manager that includes features like on-demand starting of daemons, mount and automount point maintenance, snapshot support, and processes tracking using Linux control groups.
In simple terms, it helps us manage the lifecycle of services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if there was no Gravity?</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/no-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 17:59:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/no-gravity/</guid>
      <description>We know that gravity is a force of attraction between two bodies due to their masses. More the mass of a body, higher the gravitational force it exerts. Gravity is what keeps us on the ground (not letting us fly into space when we jump off the ground).
What happens without gravity in space? We have seen clips from the space station. Due to lack of gravity, astronauts are able to fly around the space station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC, what&#39;s that?</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 15:42:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-basics/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Iresh Sharma &amp;amp; Mridul Ganga
What is WebRTC? WebRTC stands for web real-time communication, it is an open standard for real-time communications over the internet. With Webrtc you can implement realtime video, voice and data transfer between various peers, this technology is available for almost any browser and provides native clients for most platforms including android and iOS.
What can we do with WebRTC? The application of WebRTC can range from anywhere between a simple chatting application, to full-fledged audio and video conferencing applications, file transfer applications etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC using Peerjs</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:26:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean when we say peer to peer? P2P is direct connection between two devices to transfer data to-and-fro without the need of a central server. The traffic does not go to or from any central server, but directly from one device to the other.
What is WebRTC? WebRTC stands for web real-time communications. WebRTC was not supported by all the browsers until recently and is also available in most mobile browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes what and how</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/basics-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 20:14:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/basics-k8s/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is a relatively new term which is in talks a lot. In this article I will try to explain what kubernetes is and how we can quickly get started with it.
Before you start  you should have some basic understanding of linux you should know what are containers some docker knowledge would be useful  What are containers? Containers can be seen as lightweight VMs. Though they are much different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if we could change the weather?</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/weather-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:25:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/weather-change/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if humans had control of the weather! There would be no floods or hurricanes. Farming would become much more easy. We could reverse climate change and bring any kind of weather in any region. There won’t be any extreme hot or cold weathers. There are many possibilities, but who will control the weather? What kind of weather would everyone like? How can we possibly control the weather? Could there be side effects and downsides to this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:13:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog I have tried out a lot of platforms online like wordpress, weebly, wix, tumblr, etc. This is the next step. :)
What will I post here? Did not think of anything yet. The posts can range from thought experiments, code guides and other stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>