<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MG Blog</title>
    <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MG Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:26:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mridulganga.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC using Peerjs</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:26:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/webrtc-peerjs/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean when we say peer to peer? P2P is direct connection between two devices to transfer data to-and-fro without the need of a central server. The traffic does not go to or from any central server, but directly from one device to the other.
What is WebRTC? WebRTC stands for web real-time communications. WebRTC was not supported by all the browsers until recently and is also available in most mobile browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes what and how</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/basics-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 20:14:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/basics-k8s/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is a relatively new term which is in talks a lot. In this article I will try to explain what kubernetes is and how we can quickly get started with it.
Before you start  you should have some basic understanding of linux you should know what are containers some docker knowledge would be useful  What are containers? Containers can be seen as lightweight VMs. Though they are much different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if we could change the weather?</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/weather-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:25:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/weather-change/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if humans had control of the weather! There would be no floods or hurricanes. Farming would become much more easy. We could reverse climate change and bring any kind of weather in any region. There won’t be any extreme hot or cold weathers. There are many possibilities, but who will control the weather? What kind of weather would everyone like? How can we possibly control the weather? Could there be side effects and downsides to this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:13:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mridulganga.github.io/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog I have tried out a lot of platforms online like wordpress, weebly, wix, tumblr, etc. This is the next step. :)
What will I post here? Did not think of anything yet. The posts can range from thought experiments, code guides and other stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>